<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tklarryonline.me</title>
    <description>thinking and hacking</description>
    <link>http://tklarryonline.me</link>
    <atom:link href="http://tklarryonline.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Hackathon Vietnam afterthoughts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;None of us has been working in any fields related to our idea, yet we strove to broaden our horizons. Without this stressful competition, who knows when would we be aware of the Webkit Speech Recognition integrated inside Google Chrome? Or researching on Beat Detection (big appreciation to this &lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.beatport.com/2014/web-audio/beat-detection-using-web-audio/&quot;&gt;great blog post&lt;/a&gt;, very timely) and Pitch Analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about Speech Recognition and Speech-to-Text technologies, here is one of our samples used in this Hackathon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From the awesome Fight Club movie&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;audio controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/files/blog/after-hackathon/fight-club-welcome.mp3&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot; &gt;
    &lt;embed src=&quot;/files/blog/after-hackathon/fight-club-welcome.mp3&quot; &gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is the amusing transcribed result we got from a premium Speech Recognition service:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah hey I am just like all the second like the is do not call ... I ... like somebody else I was going to ask if I do not hear from you guys in my room but it&amp;#39;s on those ... I remove your shoes or white polo as long as soon as you find ... your car is not like a hey ... whether you were doing for black ... everything with God and ... are ... I am going to start packing the video and ... oh..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course we didn&amp;#39;t use that service in our application...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br class=&quot;paragraph-break&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;All the hearts go to my team&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not the war you fight but who you fight it with the most important! This adventure is nothing without my precious friends. In the hyper race with other teams, it was our endless jokes that kept us up and alive throughout the night. We joked about everything and everyone of us, from a dumb piece of code we produced to the &amp;quot;D.D.O.S attack&amp;quot; when Hackathon teams submitted their work to ChallengePost server. Even when we failed to submit our work due to the &amp;quot;D.D.O.S attack&amp;quot;, our humor helped to calm our minds so that we could find another way around to submit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br class=&quot;paragraph-break&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Closing remarks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness is all about the adventure. Although we came back without any prize, we were all rewarded. The hacking spirits - both outside and inside - overwhelmed me with awe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, every effort well spent :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 21:33:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://tklarryonline.me/blog/after-hackathon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tklarryonline.me/blog/after-hackathon/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>For better infield form's labels</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been searching for decades on how to increase the usability of form-field&amp;#39;s label. Thus, reading this post about &lt;a href=&quot;http://viget.com/inspire/making-infield-form-labels-suck-less&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making Infield Form Labels Suck Less&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; inspired me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I myself would prefer a form with field&amp;#39;s label positioned above the field, left-indented. And the placeholder text inside the field would tell briefly what should be filled. Those together would probably bring the feeling of step-by-step, what-to-do towards the form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, using just the placeholder text are not really usable. There will be some use-cases that the user clicks on the field, placeholder text disappear and... our fellow user has to rely on their short-term memory to figure out what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the post I learned some great ways to attack the problem in term of UX. And finally felt interested in the solution idea:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended up using the tooltip approach, placing labels above their input once the input has focus. We liked this approach because the active input labels are clearly distinct from other form elements, and the same approach can be used when the design scales down to smaller screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://viget.com/inspire/making-infield-form-labels-suck-less-2&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;actual implementation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of this solution, surprisingly, was not as good as I expected. The label (as a tooltip) displayed and obscured the field above, which to me is not a good appeal. One thing that may help to overcome this problem, is to decrease the opacity a little bit to show the field above. Not right-into-the-eyes, but yet visually okay.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 01:19:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://tklarryonline.me/blog/infield-form-labels/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tklarryonline.me/blog/infield-form-labels/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Switching to Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;re many reasons why I wanted to switch my blog back-end to &lt;a href=&quot;http://Jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. One main reason is that I love &lt;a href=&quot;http://git-scm.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Git&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, even want to do almost anything in my life with &lt;strong&gt;Git&lt;/strong&gt; (well, &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt;). And Jekyll does just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speed of static HTML website is another reason. This &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.kissmetric.com/loading-time/&quot;&gt;2-second loading time&lt;/a&gt; fact comparing to my old Wordpress site 7-second loading time (cached already) is just-not-right. And this site loads for just &lt;a href=&quot;http://tools.pingdom.com/fpt/#!/jHE3s/http://tklarryonline.github.io&quot;&gt;578ms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m using a modified version of Scribble, the Jekyll theme, a nice theme to start-up. You can easily &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/muan/scribble&quot;&gt;get it on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. However, a new home needs some clean-up. So here are my to-dos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;s&gt;Create my own logo using CSS3;&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;s&gt;Increase font-size and line-height to my own needs;&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;s&gt;Modify the hyperlink appearance;&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modify the menu bar;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;s&gt;Modify the container, blockquote and codeblock;&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modify the page navigation;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modify 404 error page;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customize my footer;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from that, listening to this selected list of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mp3.zing.vn/album/Nhac-Hot-US-UK-Thang-06-2013-Various-Artists/ZWZAB7EW.html&quot;&gt;Pop music for June&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;and this post is not yet finished&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 12:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://tklarryonline.me/blog/switching-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tklarryonline.me/blog/switching-to-jekyll/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>